Sujith Gopinath

Sr. Frontend Developer

A self-taught developer with 7+ years of experience in architecting and building frontend applications for B2B and B2C startups (logistics, food delivery, mobility service-based companies, etc), I have designed and developed over 7 advanced applications from use-cases and functional requirements. At the moment, I am building applications for stealth mode startups and also contributing to open-source projects (Dev.to, etc).

$>\!\!<$	sujithgnth@gmail.com
	(+91) 9741978785
in	linkedin.com/in/sujithnath
()	github.com/sujithnath
	sujeith-gopi-nath
M	https://sujithnath.github.io/sujithnath/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Frontend Engineer - [Full-Time Freelancer]

Stack: React + Redux Hooks, TypeScript , Node, Webpack, Testing, StoryBook

12/2019 - Present

Currently consulting various startups

- Building an Ed-tech platform (SkilloVilla India) with features such as tracks, courses similar to Udemy. Implemented component modularization, context as state management and firebase for authentication purposes.
- Built a CRUD mobility platform and portal for a stealth startup (WeOne

 Norway) featuring modules such as car uploads, managing
 organization groups etc.
- Applications are built with unit testing using jest + react library, and scalable architecture which helped the products to scale up with the industrial standard.

Reference: Rahul Dhawani (https://www.linkedin.com/in/rahuldhawani/)

Sr. Frontend Engineer - Loadshare Network

Stack: React + Redux + Hooks, Node, JavaScript, TDD, Webpack, TypeScript, AWS, CI/CD pipeline

04/2018 – 09/2019 loadshare.net

Managed the whole frontend logistics application, also closely worked with designers, PM's and cross-team to understand and implement features

- Architected the platform from a legacy codebase (Angular template) to a Node + React + Redux SPA using TS, webpack, and unit test.
- Modularisation of dashboards abstraction layer for APIs, Promises, data store using redux, presentational and container components
- Improved app performance (TTI) with server rendering using with node + webpack + prefetch, splitting into assets injection, lazyloading, routing etc
- Delivered a fully functional logistics app with 13 features (audit s/m, cash on delivery, item tracking, etc)
- Built custom components like dynamic table (in-house plugin) structure allowing customizable configuration
- Took responsibility for tasks/features assigned from understanding the requirement, designing, implementation, and unit testing.

Reference: Gaurav (linkedin.com/in/g-agrawal/)

SKILLS

JavaScript/ES6+

React/Redux

Angular/AngularJS

TypeScript

Node.js/Express

Next.js

Apollo/GraphQL

Webpack

HTML5/CSS3+SCSS

Docker/Kubernetes

TDD/Unit Testing (Jest, Enzyme, React library)

StoryBook

CI/CD pipeline (GitLab, CircleCI)

D3.js

Redis

Microservices

Semantics & Accessibility

A/B testing

Scrum/Agile

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Shopify Notification Feature

 Using vanilla JavaScript, developing a feature to notify users about the Shopify products

Conducted Workshops

 On Topics such as TDD, writing good unit tests and latest ES6 features (@swiggy)

Blog on medium

Angular AOT vs JIT comparison

Frontend Developer - Swiggy

Stack: React + Redux, AngularJS, JavaScript, TDD, Webpack, Mobile hybrid, Node

05/2016 – 04/2018 swiggy.com

Managed the entire vendor application of Swiggy, also helped in scaling the application from 3000 to 25000 daily users

- Built vendor app for restaurant owners from scratch which included discount features, multi-step signup flow, push notification & user metrics
- Build new APIs using Node with express by integrating with microservices services
- Developed Vendor PWA utilising PRPL pattern, web APIs like ServiceWorker, IntersectionObserver and Push API
- Introduced self-diagnostic & communication system for vendors to catch browser issues improving CX by 30%
- Developed Vendor PWA utilising PRPL pattern, web APIs like ServiceWorker, IntersectionObserver and Push API
- Integrated few features into the android app serving as a mobile hybrid.
- Optimization using webpack such as split & load the chunks using prefetch and preload.
- A member of the Page Performance Team & secured 1st place in the Swiggy hackathon 2017.

Reference: Vinit Bothra (linkedin.com/in/vinitbothra/)

UI Developer - Pipemonk (Acquired by FreshDesk)

Stack: Angular 1, JavaScript, JQUERY, Bootstrap, SCSS, Webpack, Firebase, Responsive development

04/2015 - 05/2016

After internal transfer from previous company, I was tasked to maintain website (primarily SEO) and cloud integration application

- Built cloud app with Angular 1, A/B testing + cross-device functionality
- Implemented application with firebase for user data
- Built Pipemonk StoreFront using the EJS template to supply dynamic pages based on user location.

Reference: Vaibav (linkedin.com/in/vaibhav-sinha1989/)

UI DEVELOPER - Appiness Interactive

Stack: JavaScript, JQUERY, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS, D3, Mobile responsive.

9/2013 - 04/2015

appinessworld.com

Early Stage Service Based Startup.

- Built visualization chart with D3.js, responsive admin app for Schneider Electric
- Built a scalable, lightweight flash video player that became the standard video player in custom ad units

EDUCATION

Bachelors Engineering: Mahatma Gandhi University (08/2008 – 04/2012)

Major in Electronics of Communication